In this demo, we'll be creating a program that utilizes the switch statement.
Once you're ready, fire up Visual Studio Code, and let's go.
Once we're in Visual Studio Code, click on the demo folder, or on the switch demo.
So scroll down to the switch folder, and then double click on switch dot go.
So you'll see we have a little bit of code here already.
We have a price function, which returns one, and some constants.
We have an economy, business, and first class.
We haven't covered cons very much, but it's just like a variable, except you can't change it.
So const is just short for constant.
In our main function, we're going to create a switch statement.
So we'll switch on p, and we'll create that variable, and we'll create the value from the price function.
We'll then create some cases.
So we'll use case expressions.
So in the case is less than two, when p is less than two, we'll print out a message.
So we'll have a cheap item for the message.
If the case is less than 10, we'll say that it's moderately priced.
And the default case will be expensive item.
So remember with cases, they're checked from top to bottom.
So if it's less than two, and this executes, then this one here will not execute.
So you won't get cheap item followed by moderately priced item.
That won't happen.
So if we have the case of p, and the price is one, for example.
So if we scroll up, we'll see that our price function does return one.
So this case will be executed first, and then nothing else gets checked after that.
We're going to create another case.
So we'll create a ticket, and this will be an economy seating ticket.
We'll then switch on the ticket.
And the case of an economy ticket will print out economy seating.
In the case of a business ticket, we'll print out business seating.
And in the case of first class, we'll print out first class seating.
Any other tickets will have a default.
I'll just print out other.
We're using the word economy here, because that's defined as a constant here.
So it's like I said, it's just like a variable.
So we have economy, business, and first class, zero, one, and two.
So we're just working with integers.
So when we switch on the ticket, if the ticket is economy, we'll get economy seating.
It's business, business seating, first class, first class seating, anything else,
then we're going to get other seating.
If we take a look at our code, we'll see that the first thing that prints out
should be cheap item, because our price is actually equal to one when we call the
function.
And we have an economy ticket, and so we should get economy seating printed out.
So it should be a cheap item followed by economy seating.
Now I'm going to hop into a terminal, and we'll give it a go.
You can run this with gorun.slash demo slash switch.
And there we go.
We have a cheap item and economy seating.
This concludes the demo on the switch statement.
I'll see you in the next presentation.